JULIA CHEN 6138905527

Github LinkedIn Personal Website chenjy527@gmail.com

Master in web design, experienced in web Development, more in front-end develop and working within agile team. Create WordPress theme and modify shopify Fluid template. Skilled with Adobe design tools, Focused on UX design with proven knowledge to create from concept to prototype.

SKILLS

Design Skills: Sketching, Wireframing, Prototyping, UI/UX Design, Responsive Web Design, Interactive Design

Develop Skills: HTML, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript/jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass/Less, PHP, AJAX, WordPress, Github, Joomla

Design tool: Photoshop, Adobe XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Invision

Motion Graphic: Adobe Premiere, After Effect, Adobe Animate

Language: English, Chinese

EDUCATION

Algonquin College Jan 2019 - Current

Graduate Certificate Interactive Media Management

 Relative Courses: Web Design, UX Design, Web Development, Graphic Applications, Video Compositions, Motion Graphic Effects, Rich Media Services, Database and Server-Side Development, Dynamic Media

University of Ottawa Sep 2013 - May 2015

Master of System Science

 Relative Courses: Fundamentals of Modelling and Simulation, Mobile Commerce Technologies, Principles of Formal Software Development, System Integration, System Optimization and Management

Nanjing Tech University Sep 2009 - Jun 2013

Bachelor of Information System Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer & Design Help, OTTAWAZINE global Inc, Ottawa

Dec 2018 - Now

- Shopify website improvement with plugin and theme edit.
- Functional changing as well as UI update in Shopify website by fluid.
- WordPress website maintains with HTML, JS, Bootstrap, and CSS. Fix themes with the needed requirement .
- Website redesign and handling some banner design using PS and AI.
- Magazine page design and content modify in Id.

Android APP UI detail modification as well as content edit and uploading to google play.

Web Developer, PubliVate Inc, Ottawa

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018

- Designed and developed Joomla websites with technical specifications
- Rewrote Joomla template with PHP to create multiple websites
- UI design and implement with HTML, JS, Bootstrap, Sass, Less and CSS with responsive layout
- Minifying CSS and JavaScript and compressing img using Grunt and Gulp
- Code management in Bitbucket and git
- Agile team working; continually improve process delivery effectiveness; Deadline Driven;

Business Analysis (Supply Chain Base), Oriental Food Centre Distribution Inc., Toronto

Jun 2016 - May

2017

- Assist the team to establish the supply system platform and analysis the system structure to determine the overall effectiveness; Using SQL and CPMA standard of PLU code for Data entry
- Offering superb client services and quick solutions through phone calls and face to face interactions to decrease 90% of the complaints and drastically increasing customer satisfaction
- Collaborates with Store Managers to administer the lifecycle of supplier agreements/contracts
- Follow up with Accounting to track the check process and provide reliable financial information of reports to assist manager process the strategic decision

PROJECTS

AC Interactive media management Website

- Transfered the Website code to the Client's preferred Content Management System Wordpress
- Create Explainer video to helped with client transition to help them understand how to use the CMS
- embedded JS and CSS file to fix duplicate problem

Demo Reel 2019

- Illustrated work project Demo Reel for 2019
- Drafted through storyboard, produced main character in illustrator. Finalized in Adobe After Effect

Personal WordPress Website

- Create personal website from scratch in HTML CSS and JS plugin.
- Transfer into WordPress theme with full functional menu, and sidebar.
- Customized layout and post on each page.

FoodSafety Website redesign

- Redesign Website Logo and layout using AI, make it ease of use.
- Change color scheme choose more reasonable color to fit the page
- Redesign website layout using PS

Teashop Website design

- Design Teashop website layout for mobile view and desktop view using PS
- Responsive layout build by Bootstrap, HTML and CSS
- Dark color chose to match shop style.

Typography Poster

- Poster made only by typography in AI.
- Create meaningful building shape according to travel theme

Pettown Website design

- Pettown design brief and strategy research
- Create mobile view as well as desktop view for responsive
- Light beige color to increase user usability and visibility

CSS Zengarden

• Creating a unique design for CSSZenGarden.com with only CSS. without any changes with HTML.

Mail Flow Service

- Designed custom mail service front-end page template which supported adding / editing email content and sending email through different content with responsive layout
- Implemented back-end restful application with custom defined route controller and single service entrance
- Connected front-end page and restful application using jQuery ajax and dynamically generated html structure
- Integrated mail service with third-party API (Mandrill) to support mail state monitoring and mail distribution
- Built research document and shared with company team about Mandrill integration

REWARD

Dean's Honours List

Jun 2019 | Faculty of Arts, Media and Design

Placed on the Dean's Honours List for outstanding academic achievement

The Dean's Honours List recognizes students who have demonstrated academic excellence by maintaining a grade point average of at least 3.60

CERTIFICATE

| • | People Analytics | University of Pennsylvania on Coursera Verified Certificates |
|---|--|--|
| • | Competitive Strategy | University of Pennsylvania on Coursera Verified Certificates |
| • | Operation Analytics | University of Pennsylvania on Coursera Verified Certificates |
| • | Customer Analytics | University of Pennsylvania on Coursera Verified Certificates |
| • | Rig Data and Information Dissemination | Fudan University on Coursera Verified Certificates |